我们给出的使用检查异常规则
The rule we've given use checked exceptions
对于它的一些预期情况
for some of its anticipated situations and unchecked
信号错误的异常，如意外故障。
exceptions to signal bugs, like unexpected failures.
这是有道理的，但这不是故事的结尾
This will make sense, but it isn't the end of the story
问题是Java中的异常
and the snag is that exceptions in Java
并不像它们那么轻。
aren't as lightweight as they might be.
现在是表演罚分
Now there's a performance penalty
引发异常，但更重要的是
for throwing an exception, but more importantly
Java中的异常会导致另一个更严重的交叉。
exceptions in Java incur another more serious cross.
对程序员来说是一种痛苦
They're a pain for the programmer
在设计方法和使用方法中使用。
to use, both in designing methods and using methods.
如果您设计一个方法来拥有自己的新异常，
If you design a method to have its own new exception,
必须为异常创建一个新类。
you have to create a new class for the exception.
如果调用可以引发选中异常的方法，
If you call a method that can throw a checked exception,
你必须用try/catch语句来包装它
you have to wrap it in a try/catch statement
即使你知道例外永远不会
even if you know the exception will never
即使你能证明
be thrown-- even if you can prove
那是你自己设计的。
that to yourself by design.
现在，后一个规定让人左右为难——所以假设，
Now the latter stipulation makes a dilemma-- so suppose,
例如，您正在设计队列数据结构。
for example, you're designing a queue data structure.
弹出队列会引发选中的异常
Should popping the queue throw a checked exception
当队列为空时？
when the queue is empty?
好吧，假设你想支持一种编程风格
Well, suppose you want to support a style of programming
在循环中弹出队列的客户端
the client in which the queue is popped in the loop
直到抛出异常，所以
until the exception is thrown, so you
为设计选择选中的异常。
choose a checked exception for your design.
但现在其他一些客户想在上下文中使用该方法
But now some other client wants to use the method in a context
其中在弹出客户之前，
in which immediately prior to popping the client,
它已经测试了队列是否为空并且仅
it has already tested whether the queue is empty and only
如果不是的话会流行。
pops if it isn't.
现在令人抓狂的是，那个客户
Now maddeningly, that client will still
需要用try/catch语句包装调用，
need to wrap the call in a try/catch statement,
即使那个客户确信
even though that client is convinced
队列不是空的。
that the queue is not empty.
所以这建议了一个更精细的设计规则--
So this suggests a more refined design rule--
您应该只使用未检查的异常
you should use an unchecked exception only
发出意外失败的信号，或者如果您希望客户机
to signal an unexpected failure or if you expect that clients
通常会编写代码以确保异常不会
will usually write code that ensures the exception will not
因为有一个方便又便宜的方法
happen because there's a convenient and inexpensive way
以避免例外。
to avoid the exception.
否则，应使用选中的异常。
Otherwise, you should use a checked exception.
下面是一些应用此规则的示例
Now here's some examples of applying this rule
假设的方法。
to hypothetical methods.
对于我们的队列示例，queue.pop可以抛出未经检查的空
For our queue example, queue.pop could throw an unchecked empty
队列为空时出现队列异常
queue exception when the queue is empty
因为有理由期望打电话的人避免这样做
because it's reasonable to expect the caller to avoid this
通过以前调用queue.size或queue.isempty。
by previously making a call like queue.size or queue.isempty.
具有get web page entry方法的URL类
A URL class with a get web page entry method
它应该下载URL引用的网页
that's supposed to download the web page that the URL refers
如果不能，则需要抛出一个选中的IOException
to would need to throw a checked IOException when it can't
检索网页，因为调用者不容易
retrieve the web page because it's not easy for the caller
为了防止这种情况。
to prevent this.
这是一个预期的失败，打电话的人不能真的
It's an anticipated failure that the caller can't really
在不尝试下载网页的情况下阻止。
prevent without trying to download the web page.
类似地，整数平方根方法
Similarly, an integer square root method
获取一个整数并返回一个整数
takes an integer and returns an integer
应该只返回平方根
and should only return that square root
如果x是一个完美的正方形。
if x is a perfect square.
你会希望它抛出一个checked not perfect square异常
You'd want it to throw a checked not perfect square exception
当x没有积分平方根时，因为测试x是否
when x has no integral square root because testing whether x
一个完美的正方形对客户来说同样困难
is a perfect square is just as hard for the client
找到实际的平方根。
as finding the actual square root.
指望打电话的人阻止是不合理的。
It's not reasonable to expect the caller to prevent it.
现在在Java中使用异常的代价
Now the cost of using exceptions in Java
是许多Java API不幸
is one reason that many Java APIs unfortunately
请将空引用用作特殊值。
do use the null reference as a special value.
以下是一些可以滥用异常的方法
Here's some ways that exceptions can be abused
这个例子来自于Josh Bloch的杰出著作
and this example comes from Josh Bloch's outstanding book
我建议使用有效的Java
Effective Java, which I recommend
你读过的第二版第57条。
that you read-- it's Item 57 in the second edition.
那么这个代码是做什么的呢？
So what does this code do?
嗯，它在做循环。
Well, it's doing the loop.
我是一个从0开始的索引
i is an index that is starting from 0
每次通过这个循环递增
and being incremented each time through this loop
它被用作这个数组的索引
and it's used as an index into this array, that
是一个对象数组，然后我们调用一个方法，
is an array of objects that we're then calling a method up,
好吗？
all right?
所以我们在这些物体中循环
So we're looping through this array of objects
并对数组中的每个元素调用f方法
and calling the f method on each element in the array
然后，一旦我太兴奋了
and then, once i gets too high, it's
将抛出数组索引越界异常，
going to throw an array index out of bounds exception,
跳出那个循环，被这个catch语句捕获，
break out of that loop, be caught by this catch statement,
什么也不做，继续前进。
do nothing, and move on.
所以它是一个无限循环，终止于
So it's an infinite loop that terminates
通过抛出、捕获和忽略超出边界的数组
by throwing, catching, and ignoring an array out of bounds
一旦[听不见]就例外
exception as soon as it [INAUDIBLE] that's
数组边界之外的第一个数组元素。
the first array element outside the bounds of the array.
现在它应该相当于
Now it's supposed to be equivalent to the much more
这三个元素for循环的熟悉而惯用的版本
familiar and idiomatic version of this three element for loop
或者更简单的事情，
statement or even the simpler thing,
这只是每个循环的
which is just the for each that loops
通过数组的元素
through the elements of the array
其中大写T是任意类型的
where capital T is whatever the type is
那个数组的元素。
of the elements of that array.
现在这个基于异常的版本是block
Now this exception-based version as block
写是一个非常错误的尝试，以提高性能。
writes is a very misguided attempt to improve performance.
它基于错误推理，因为虚拟机
It's based on faulty reasoning that since the virtual machine
正在检查这些数组访问的边界，
is checking the bounds of these array accesses already,
正常回路终止试验--
the normal loop termination test--
这个——实际上是多余的，应该
this one-- is actually redundant and should
避开，好吗？
be avoided, all right?
所以这个和这个之间有多余的检查。
So there is redundant checking between this and this.
不幸的是，因为Java中的异常
Unfortunately, because exceptions in Java
仅在特殊情况下使用，
are designed for use only under exceptional circumstances,
大多数jvm并不试图优化其性能。
most JVMs do not attempt to optimize their performance.
一个基于异常的习惯用法，比如这个循环，
An exception-based idiom, like this loop,
可能比标准的慢70倍
may actually run 70 times slower than the standard one
当它只循环通过几个值时
when it's looping through only a few values like only
100个值。
100 values.
现在更糟的是，基于异常的习惯用法
Now much worse than that, the exception-based idiom
甚至不能保证工作。
is not even guaranteed to work.
它在这里调用这个函数f。
It's calling this function f here.
假设有一个bug导致了越界
Suppose there's a bug that results in an out of bounds
访问一些不相关的数组。
access to some unrelated array.
会发生什么事？
What's going to happen?
代码中会发生什么
What's going to happen in this code
如果f碰巧抛出数组索引越界异常？
if f happens to throw an array index out of bounds exception?
好吧，如果合理的循环习语
Well, if the reasonable loop idiom
如果使用该漏洞将生成一个未察觉的异常，
were used that bug would generate an uncaught exception,
导致立即终止具有完整堆栈的线程
resulting in an immediate thread termination with a full stack
追踪。
trace.
但是如果使用这个版本的话
But if this version is used, that bug in f
会被抓在这里蒙面。
is going to get caught here and masked.
你会把失败的速度变成一个循环
You will have turned what was a fail fast into a loop
终止和不检查。
termination and no checking.
这个程序将继续运行并做错误的事情。
The program will just roll on and do the wrong thing.